# Richard Kennedy

# Frontend developer

## **PROFILE**

Im an Australian who moved to Stockholm in 2015 with my Swedish partner. I am a very passionate, thoughtful and positive person who is very goal-orientated. I really enjoy bringing that energy into the teams that I work with.

I have been an electrician for almost 10 years and decided I wanted to follow a passion of mine, Which has led me to Hyper Island to study Frontend Development. I am now interning at Mobiento / Deloitte Digital and hope to secure a junior developer role early 2023. .

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Frontend Developer Intern

Mobiento / Deloitte Digital

Sep 2022 - Present, Stockholm

Building an Unsplash clone as my intern task. familiarizing myself with React | Typescript | Unit Testing | Bitbucket

# Frontend Development

Aug 2021 - Present, Stockholm

Currently studying frontend development at Hyper Island.

Project-based learning individually and in teams,

Adapting an agile mindset to my development process and learning to create beautiful web applications.

## Industrial/Commercial Electrician

Norrsken Elinstallationer

Jan 2016 - Aug 2021 - 5 years, Stockholm

## **Supervisor Construction Electrician**

Civmec Engineering & Goodline electrical

jan 2015 - Dec 2015 - 1 year, Port Hedland, Australia

#### **Apprentice Electrician**

Changeovers PTY LTD

jan 2011 - jan 2015 - 4 years, Perth, Australia

## **EDUCATION**

## **CERTIFICATE III in Electrotechnology Electrician**

North Metropolitan TAFE

# **CONTACT**

Richardgrahamkennedy@gmail.com

+46 73 833 29 99

Tappvägen 27

168 78 Stockholm, Sweden

# **Industry Knowledge**

Product Design & development Agile development process Working in teams SEO & Accessibility Wireframing Prototyping Design Research

# **Skills**

HTML, CSS, SCSS, Tailwind, Javascript, Phaser.JS, React.JS, Figma, GitHub, MongoDB, Typescript, Unittesting

# **Hobies**

Coding, Surfing, Snowboarding, Coffee, Interior design, Fashion, MUSIC

# Language

English (professional)
Swedish (learning)

# LinkedIn

Github

My Portfolio

# Richard Kennedy

# Frontend developer

# **Professional Highlights**

2022 -

Unsplash Clone - (React / Typescript / Tailwind / Jest )

Re-creating Unsplash using the Unsplash API.

This project comes with a clean UI that features a search-bar, the classic unsplash masonry grid layout for my image gallery, a category list that routes dynamically, placeholders for slow loading and its all responsive. What I have learned most from this project is the importance of testing and how to write much cleaner code for eg - useContext as oppose to prop drilling, reusing components and functionality.

2022 -

E-commerce Happenings – An experience package

Frontend & Backend (React / Tailwind / JavaScript / MongoDB) I collaborated in a team to build and deploy an e-commerce application that provides experiences such as whale-watching, salsa dancing etc, where all products chosen are taken through a checkout process. I was responsible for the database architecture, developing user friendly interactions, responsiveness, rendering the items in the database and creating an individual information page for selected items.

#### **3D GAME WHACK-A-CRAB**

2022 -

Frontend (JavaScript / A-frame)

I built and deployed a 3D game that I presented at the Hyper Island game conference. I implemented 3D models and a 3D environment into the game that is interactable through the use of JavaScript and A-Frame functionalities.

# **WEBSITE Travel advice**

2022 -

Frontend & Backend (Next.js / React / Tailwind / MongoDB)

I Built and deployed an application that allowed users to search for a country or city and be given advice on where to eat, stay and discover. I created a database that stores content and uses a frontend stack of Next.js, React and Tailwind to render the content.

ARCADE GAME Space Invaders

2021 -

Frontend (JavaScript / Phaser.js)

I collaborated in a small team to build and deploy a 2D game using Phaser.js. This game was to be presented to the Hyper Island FED23 class once complete. I was responsible for creating a parallax background, shooter functionality, invaders to disappear on collision and a scoreboard.